October 9th, Stellar Year 2149
We've started our advance again.
Time since operation start
According to that boy
with the strange powers,
the Morpho is stopped on the tracks
in southern Legion-held territory.
The Federacy's main force,
as well as the Alliance,
will advance and take the area
around the tracks.
The United Kingdom will be working
with another
smaller Federacy unit to take tracks
on the north side.
So the United Kingdom volunteered
to be a diversion?
But if the Federacy's main army advances,
the Legion's not going to miss that.
What's our plan?
The Alliance is going to be using
a prototype anti-radar weapon.
It disperses clouds of small
metal particles into the air,
jamming communications among the Legion.
If they use everything they have,
the hope is they can buy enough time
for the Legion to identify
the United Kingdom's force as the big one.
They're going all-in.
The Legion learn fast,
so this kind of thing only works once.
If we lose this, it's over.
What else could they do?
The Federacy's the same, right?
Everyone's forced to do
whatever it takes, huh?
They're on the move.
The Legion?
They fell for the diversion to the north.
A double diversion, huh?
The guys to the north
and south are desperate, huh?
That means the main force
will finally move, too.
We won't be that far after all.
The Federacy's main force
will be doing an all-night march.
That should get them closer, but...
True.
I don't care if they can't catch up, but...
Shin. Take Frederica and go back.
Why?
You know why.
Somebody needs to get her past
all those Legion without being found.
Only you can do that.
And our pursuit?
If he can move only on the train tracks,
we can probably track him
just talking through Para-RAID.
Fortunately, unlike last time,
somebody is making a big distraction for us.
You think the Legion will be forced
to use all their forces
to deal with the diversion
and the main unit?
You know from the last time we passed through
Legion territory that fighting means instant death.
It'd be better than having you lead us,
the way you are now.
You've always been crazy,
but that last fight was too much.
Something had control of you...
I don't know if it's this ghost knight
of Frederica's you've never met, but...
What's gotten into you?
Nothing.
You really think you can fool me
that easily? Idiot.
Fool you?
I'm afraid
we've known each other a long time.
I can see a few things
you yourself can't.
You're such a mess
that you can barely stand.
So you're back to where you were
when we met?
Never opening up to anyone...
Like the name everyone calls you...
The Reaper...
Then the rest of you
can take her and go.
I'd rather follow it myself
than take someone who'll slow me down.
What?
If this is a one-way mission,
it's better I go myself.
If you're intending to go home,
there's no need to follow a path of no return.
You...!
Don't think you can keep everybody
else alive by doing this.
What do you mean, "one-way mission"?
Don't talk like you're not coming back!
I'm not planning to die.
Yeah, I bet.
But you weren't planning
on coming back alive, either!
Why did you kill your brother?
Wasn't it so you could keep going forward?
You didn't survive all that
just to kill your brother, did you?
Don't misunderstand that!
Then...
Then why...
Why did I...
I don't want to die.
That's all.
And I think that's enough.
I'm pretty sure
the others feel the same way.
It's your path to walk. You decide.
But...
We're all traveling the same road together.
If you're exhausted, we'll support you.
If you're tired, rest!
So...
Don't try to fight on your own.
It kinda feels like I'm being left out...
Like I'm not being treated like a fellow guy.
They've known each other a long time.
Supposedly a lot happened
before we met them.
Is that how it is?
Stay put.
It's your fault for trying
to run over and interrupt them.
You were like a little dog!
Even if you did go, you'd just
make things more complicated.
Stay put.
That's not true!
What Raiden said about something
having control of him is probably true.
Shin's been acting weird for a while.
Thinking back,
he's been weird ever since then.
Before, he'd never do anything that meant
certain death, or let anybody else do so.
Shin is fine.
He wouldn't leave us.
I think you should try
to face Shin as he really is
and not just see him
as an ideal in your head.
Shin's not going to be our
personal Reaper forever, right?
You were always worried
about that, right, Anju?
We're similar, after all.
I know a little about what a child feels
when their family says they're not needed.
They wonder if it's their fault.
They might know in their head that it isn't,
but they still blame themselves.
Especially since Shin wasn't just told...
by his brother.
You can't get rid
of things like that by yourself.
Does that mean that our just being
there for him isn't enough?
All we've been able to do is ask him
to stay with us till we die.
We were just relying on him
and intending to leave him someday.
Even though I'm sure that was the first time
he said he'd go on ahead of us...
They said the Republic isn't responding
to radio calls.
Essentially, the country must have ceased to exist.
Probably.
So they were wiped out after all.
The Major wasn't able
to catch up with us, huh?
Just so you know, Kurena,
this is your big chance.
They say when somebody's feeling depressed,
it's easier to take advantage of them.
Huh?
Just so you know, Theo,
it's only bad girls who do that.
That wouldn't be right for Kurena.
I suppose that's true.
No! I don't...
Do you think Shin knows?
I would say he's long-since realized,
but thinks it's more of a childish
admiration and possessiveness?
He seems to think of you as a little sister
who is particularly difficult to deal with.
I don't think he sees you
as a woman at all, to be honest.
Well... You're someone he can count on.
Frederica, there are some things
you just shouldn't say!
That's enough, right?
Y-Yeah.
I'm a good sniper! I'm useful!
Don't worry.
I'm not going to run off on my own.
I would feel better if I did, though.
General, it's time to wake up.
What are the Eighty-Six doing?
We were finally able
to synchronize with them.
This Republic technology is very useful.
You've finally connected?
It routes through your consciousness.
If you're asleep, you can't be contacted.
October 10th, Stellar Year 2149
I can't believe a five-man force is able
to get any sleep so deep in enemy territory.
The battlefield is daily life for them, huh?
Where do you think they are now?
They're 120 kilometers west of the old border.
We could march all night and still not catch up.
It's a little frustrating.
I'm surprised.
I thought you wanted to ensure
they didn't survive this battle.
You seem to misunderstand me.
I just think that a sharp blade
should be put to good use.
If we can use that blade a long time,
all the better.
We can't have the Legion taking them.
We need to get them back fast.
We're starting our march before dawn.
Y-You guys...
Roger. We're ready to go whenever.
We're not packing much equipment,
as you can see.
Are you worried about them, Sergeant?
I'll ask you the same question.
We did all we could.
Now we just have to believe.
You say that, but just in case, you've brought
extra Reginleifs, ammo, spare parts,
along with a repair crew,
all the way from the front lines.
You even forced the Chief of Staff
to authorize their transport by air.
And I suggested you go back
to the front lines, and you refused.
What kind of man would I be if I did?
If the kids come back
after catching their big centipede,
and all the old men are drinking,
they'd make fun of us
till the day we died.
Those little brats would.
Not good.
Can you get it out, Theo?
I don't think so.
It's not moving at all.
I'm purging it.
Laughing Fox was damaged, too, huh?
We're taking more damage
than expected.
Anju and I got some shrapnel
the other day.
And when you were blasted back,
you lost a machine gun.
Only Undertaker's safe, huh?
He's out of spare blades, though.
No, my engine hasn't been
working right since yesterday.
I think I put too much stress on it
during the first battle.
You haven't fixed your bad habit
of destroying your Reginleif's legs?
I think I can keep it patched up
with repairs for a short while.
If nothing else,
it's not so bad that I can't move.
But if you put too much stress on it,
it'll break.
Don't get too crazy.
Given the amount of ammo
and energy packs we have on hand,
tomorrow will be the last day
of our pursuit.
We'll probably catch up to it
before that,
but it would be a good idea
to ensure we last until then.
Until we catch up to it, huh?
Roger.
It's like the sea...
Have any of you seen the sea?
I don't think I have.
I thought I saw it once on a transport
between combat districts,
but looking back, I may have been wrong.
Not the sea, but there was a big lake near me.
I'd go there to play a lot.
My elementary school had a field trip
to take kids to the ocean.
But the war started first.
Me, neither.
I've never seen anything like this before.
There's so much I don't know.
I want to go see the ocean.
I want to go swimming!
I'm sure it's a lot of fun!
The sea, huh?
Yeah, that might be fun!
How about a tropical island?
Coral, coconut trees, white beaches.
I'd love to see a sea of ice
in the north, too!
They say when it's really cold,
you can walk across it!
Wow!
Where'd you hear that?
I saw it in a pamphlet
for a travel company.
Let's go!
All of us, when the war's over!
Fido.
I ordered you to switch to standby mode
until I wake you up tomorrow.
Fine. If that's what you want to do.
I thought it was weird
to hear you talking so much.
It's cause you're talking to Fido, huh?
What is it?
I felt that I understood you a little today.
I looked at the scenery the whole time.
It was so beautiful.
If you've lived your whole lives
surrounded by that scenery,
then I felt that
maybe I could understand the reason.
The reason you're so disinterested
in humanity's survival, and your own lives.
That beauty exists only because
there are no humans here.
Maybe that scenery is what the Legion want.
I don't know.
They may not want anything.
They're ghosts.
Ghosts aren't supposed to want anything.
How do you know?
Because I'm the same.
That night, I failed to die.
And I think I'm still dead.
Ever since then,
I haven't been able to want anything.
I don't want to see the sea.
I don't have anything I want to do
or any place where I want to go.
It doesn't really cause me any problems,
but I kind of understand now
that not even being able
to have something small you want to do—
like our conversation at dusk—is bizarre.
But last fall was fun, wasn't it?
When you left the eighty-six districts.
It was the first time you were able
to decide everything for yourself—
the first time you had freedom, right?
It was fun.
Because I thought it would be over soon.
I thought we'd die without anyone
ever knowing what happened to us.
But we survived, unfortunately...
I was supposed to die.
The future is too long
for someone like me.
I'm not your knight.
I knew that, but...
I'm sorry for using your knight
as an excuse.
I'm still going to go as far as I can.
But my brother isn't there anymore.
So I wanted another goal
that would take his place for a while.
I don't think that's all.
You should be aware that you're looking
in the mirror the wrong way.
You're not nearly as cold
as you think you are.
You're a softie, Reaper.
If nothing else, I can release Kiri
because you agreed to help me.
It was so sad, seeing him crying and
trapped deep within the battlefield.
I wanted to free him.
I wanted to be freed from being forced
to see his misery.
But...
I'm scared of Kiri dying.
I'm terrified of losing him.
The Federacy doesn't need a child like me.
It's a republic now.
Just by being alive,
I could potentially start a war.
It's better for everyone if I'm not here.
But I thought I had to stay alive
to put an end to my knight's life.
But when Kiri dies,
that excuse will cease to exist.
And that scares me.
The reason you're terrified
of going forward right now
is that you tried to see the future
for what it is!
Because you tried to look directly
at the dark, untrodden path before you!
No.
It's nothing to be ashamed of,
and while you're doing it, at least,
you let those who are with you support you.
That's what companions are for.
That's why people come together.
Raiden said the same thing.
Then just admit he was right—
I'm not like them.
Not having any wishes is the same
as not wanting to be alive.
I'm the only one of us
who still isn't truly alive.
I'm just the Reaper.
And the ones who call me that
will someday go on ahead...
and leave me behind.
October 11th, Stellar Year 2149
Pale Rider to No-Face.
Beginning combat operations.
No-Face, roger.
There is new information to share
from the wide-area network.
We've found traces of an enemy unit
within our territory.
From the available information,
it appears they are pursuing you.
You are to begin searching for them
in the vicinity of your operations area.
Roger.
"All that's left."